(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
すてきなホリデイ
Suteki na Holiday (Wonderful Holiday)
近づいている冬の足音
The footsteps of winter are drawing near.
耳を澄ませば聞こえる鈴の音
If you listen closely, you can hear the sound of bells.
寝ぼけた頭に響く目覚ましを
The alarm clock ringing in my sleepy head,
手さぐりで止めたあと雪の気配
After fumbling to stop it, I sense the snow.
始まりを告げるすてきな季節が
The wonderful season that signals a beginning is here.
Happy holidays, happy holidays
What a glorious time of year!
すやすやと眠る子供達の手に
In the hands of children sleeping soundly,
抱かれたテディベアももう待ちきれない
Even the teddy bears they hold can't wait any longer.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
As if to wipe away all the sad things that happened.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Come on, take off your pajamas and let's go out.
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
Dashing through the trees lining the street as they slowly turn white.
街は急ぎ足
The town is in a hurry.
贈り物決まる頃 顔ほころんでく
Faces light up as gifts are decided.
かじかんだ指を
My numb fingers,
ママが温めるね
Mom warms them up.
Happy holidays, happy holidays
What a glorious time of year!
大切なものは
The important things,
みんなそばにある
Are all right beside you.
穏やかな毎日が
Peaceful days,
続くぜいたく
The luxury of them continuing.
クリスマスがもうじきやって来る
Christmas is coming soon.
うれしさをかくせない犬や猫まで
Even dogs and cats can't hide their joy.
もみの木に灯る明かりをうけて
Bathed in the lights of the fir tree,
いつもよりやさしそうなパパの目が笑ってる
Dad's eyes seem kinder than usual as he smiles.
クリスマスは誰にもやって来る
Christmas comes for everyone.
もしひとりぼっちでも淋しがらずに
Even if you're all alone, don't be lonely.
心に住むサンタに呼びかけて
Call out to the Santa living in your heart.
幼い頃の夢を思い出してごらんよ
Try to remember the dreams of your childhood.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year.
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
As if to erase sad events.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Come on, take off your pajamas and let's go out.
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
Running through the trees turning white bit by bit.
Happy happy holidays
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the city like a whipped cake
好き！雪！本気マジック
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti the sky gives us
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ Woo
Are angel wings celebrating the winter fiesta, Woo!
銀色の国へ
To the silver country,
出かけるの Go Go Go
Let's head out, Go Go Go!
雪の汽車が
The snow train,
街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
Runs through the town, Choo Choo Choo!
絵本みたいな景色を
The scenery like a picture book,
君に見せてあげるから
I'll show it to you.
願い込めて呪文 今 唱えて
With a wish, chant the spell now!
ABCD ドドシララシ
ABCD Do-Do-Si-La-La-Si
マジカルミラクルクル Pop!
Magical miracle-cle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the city like a whipped cake,
好き！雪！本気マジック
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti the sky gives us,
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
Are angel wings celebrating the winter fiesta.
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は
The lit-up aurora-colored city,
好き！雪！本気マジック
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If we could stay children, Dream Land!
Ladies and gentlemen! Welcome to Snow Miko!
ツンと冷たい季節が好き
I love the biting cold season!
Love Love Love
アイスも魔法もとけないように
So the ice and magic won't melt,
ヒューヒューヒュー
Pew pew pew!
ずっとこのままじゃダメなの？
Can't we stay like this forever?
やっぱりドキドキしたいな
I want to feel my heart pound after all.
未来求め呪文 今 唱えて
Seeking the future, chant the spell now!
1234 水金地火木
1 2 3 4 Mercury Venus Earth Mars Jupiter
マジカルミラクルクル Pop!
Magical miracle-cle Pop!
Ah ホップしたウサギのような気分
Ah, feeling like a hopping rabbit.
好き！雪！本気マジック
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
大地がくれる元気 得たら
Once we get the energy the earth gives,
思い通り明日を生きていけるよ
We can live tomorrow just the way we want.
まぶしい白に染まるハート君に
My heart dyed in dazzling white, for you,
好き！雪！本気マジック
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
大人のふりなんていいじゃん
It's okay not to pretend to be an adult.
I hear that beat from town
The cute angel will come down
This is my home I'll let you know
NAMARA fantastic!
The snowscape is lyrical
The street gonna be magical
I'll set you free in my land oh oh oh
今日の寒さも忘れるように（わすれちゃって）
So you can forget today's cold (forget it all)
悩みだって恨みだって凍らせて
Freeze away your worries and your grudges
消せる魔法よ（もっかい）
It's magic that can erase them (one more time)
ABCDドシラソファミレシドマジカルミラクルクルPop!
A-B-C-D Do-Ti-La-So-Fa-Mi-Re-Do Magical Miracle Kuru-Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town is like a whipped cream cake
好き雪マジマジ
Love, snow, serious, serious
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti given by the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
Are angel wings celebrating the winter festival
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は
The town lit up in aurora colors is
好き雪本気Magic
Love, snow, true magic
子供でいられたらDream Land
If we could stay children, it's a Dream Land
いいな
How nice
いいじゃん！
Isn't it great!
君の前では私（私）
In front of you, I (I)
らしくいていいよね？（いいよね）
Can be myself, right? (Right?)
弱気で流したジングル
The jingle I played timidly
いつもドキドキだね第一声
The first voice is always heart-pounding
にゃっはろ〜！
Nyahallo~!
震えた声もノートの文字も
My trembling voice and the words in my notebook
みんなみんな手繋いでGO!
Everyone, everyone, hold hands and GO!
変わってるねって（そーなんだ）
They say I'm weird (Is that so?)
なんて言ったの？（まぁいっか）
What did you say? (Well, whatever)
飲み込んじゃってきた言葉も
Even the words I've been swallowing back
君と笑った声でほら咲いて
Look, they bloom with the voice laughing with you
万歳！（万歳！）
Banzai! (Banzai!)
こんな私でも（モーマンタイ！）
Even someone like me (No problem!)
好きだってねぇほんと？
You like me, really?
どっち？わかりそう？どっち？わかんない！
Which one? Can you tell? Which one? I don't know!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
受け取っていっせーのーせで
Receive it, ready, set, go!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
Something that will surely make your heart skip a beat
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで
Packed tightly into a flower bud
君の前では私（私）
In front of you, I (I)
らしくいていいよね？（いいよね？）
Can be myself, right? (Right?)
なんで改行（あっとー！）
Why a line break (Oh no!)
頭が（もっと！）素直が（もっと！）
My head (More!) Honesty (More!)
ゲームの中ならGet You!
If it's inside a game, Get You!
攻略（Chu Chu）百発（Chu Chu）中なのにね
Capture (Chu Chu) Bullseye (Chu Chu) even though it is
どったんばったん踊ったなら悩んじゃったって
If you dance around wildly, even if you're worried
Ogi Ogi
ズッキュンバッキュンスタートボタン押せるかな？
Zukkyun Bakkyun, can you press the start button?
ちゃんと言ったっけ？（どーだっけ？）
Did I say it properly? (Did I?)
言わなきゃよかった？（そーだっけ）
Should I not have said it? (Is that so?)
抑え込んじゃってまた焼きもち
Suppressing it and feeling jealous again
あー私なんてしゃがみそうになって
Ah, I almost crouch down thinking 'someone like me'
大正解！（大正解！）
Correct answer! (Correct answer!)
これが私だもん（大賛成！）
This is who I am (Totally agree!)
行くよってほらこっち！
I say 'let's go', look, over here!
右？曲がっちゃう？左？迷っちゃう？まっすぐ！
Right? Turn? Left? Get lost? Straight ahead!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
春めいて待って飛び立って
Becoming like spring, wait, fly away
そっとじっとシュンとしちゃう日も
Even on days when I feel quietly down
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
瞳にパッと映るよ
It reflects suddenly in your eyes
背中を押してメロディー
Push my back, melody
好きでいていいよね？（いいよね！）
Is it okay to keep liking you? (It's okay!)
誰かじゃなくて
Not just anyone
君がいいよって（絶対！）
It has to be you (Absolutely!)
何度でも言うよ（もう一回！）
I'll say it as many times as needed (One more time!)
好きだってねぇほんと！（もういっか！）
I like you, really! (One more time!)
どっち？わかりそう？（超特急！）
Which one? Can you tell? (Super express!)
どっち？わかんない！本当だ！
Which one? I don't know! It's true!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
受け取っていっせーのーせで
Receive it, ready, set, go!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
Something that will surely make your heart skip a beat
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで
Packed tightly into a flower bud
君の前では私（私）
In front of you, I (I)
らしくいていいよね？（いいよね？）
Can be myself, right? (Right?)
好きでいていいよね？
Is it okay to keep liking you?
はーい！にゃっはろ〜！
Haaai! Nyahallo~!
Twinkle Idol Christmas さくらみこ新衣装お披露目LIVEに
Twinkle Idol Christmas Sakura Miko New Outfit Reveal LIVE
来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
そしてみんな、メリークリスマス！
And everyone, Merry Christmas!
イェーイ！
Yaay!
えー、本日クリスマスはなんと
Um, today, Christmas is actually...
みこちゃんのホロライブ加入記念日でもあります！
...also Miko-chan's Hololive joining anniversary!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えーそしてお披露目したこちらの衣装は
Um, and this outfit I just revealed is...
200万人記念で作らせていただいた新衣装の
...the new outfit made to commemorate 2 million subscribers...
ルームウェア... ルームウェア衣装となっております！
...room wear... it is a room wear outfit!
あのね
You know...
ま いつも新衣装で悩んでるんですけど
Well, I always worry about new outfits, but...
作りたいなってずっと思ってたんだけどなかなかね
I've always wanted to make this, but I just couldn't quite...
踏み切れなかった
...take the plunge.
このルームウェアをね 200万人記念で作らしてもらいました
I was allowed to make this room wear for the 2 million subscriber commemoration.
いいアイデアだよね これね
It's a good idea, isn't it?
そして ちょ見ていただくんですけど
And, I'd like you to take a look at this.
こちら じゃじゃーん
Here it is! Ta-da!
ヘアバンド これみこぴーのヘアバンドになってます
A hairband! It's a Mikopi hairband.
ちょっとふわふわしてる かわいいし
It's a bit fluffy and cute.
ま このピンもいっぱいついてて イヤリングもかわいくって
Also, there are lots of pins, and the earrings are cute too.
あとこのサクランボになってるんですよ めっちゃネックレス かわいい
And look, the necklace is cherries! It's so cute.
で このね ダボっとしたニットに
And with this baggy knit...
ま ちょっとセクシーなね ちょっとセクシーな
It's a little sexy... a little sexy...
ルームウェアになってます これ
...room wear outfit.
あの ちょっとね なかなかね みこちゃんはおへそは見せないんですけど
Usually, Miko-chan doesn't really show her navel, but...
ちょ おへそがね 見えます
You can see my navel!
ちょっとあの若干...
It's a little bit, um...
ま 寒くなるとね 食べたくなって若干ぷにってる気はしなくもないけど
Well, when it gets cold, I eat more, so I feel like it's a bit squishy, but...
ままま 気にしたら負けですからね
Well, well, if you worry about it, you lose.
大丈夫 健康的な範囲だからね 大丈夫大丈夫
It's fine, it's within a healthy range! It's fine, it's fine.
ということで
So anyway...
あのね ま 隅々までちょっと見ていただきたいんですが
I want you to look at every corner of it, but...
もっとね 見ていただきたいところがあります
There is something else I really want you to see.
見て この
Look at this!
お部屋 かわいい
The room! It's so cute!
本日のライブはなんと トリバルコンさんにね 制作を
Today's live stage was actually produced by Tribulcon-san...
あの お願いさせていただきまして 作ってます
...I asked them to create it for me.
本当にどうもありがとうございます めっちゃかわいいの
Thank you so much! It's incredibly cute.
もう本当にね みこぴーとかね このソファとかね めちゃくちゃ細かく作っていただいております
Really, from the Mikopis to this sofa, everything was made in such detail.
この後もね ちょっとね びっくりするギミックとかもありますのでお楽しみに
There are some surprising gimmicks coming up later, so look forward to it!
じゃあね あ そうだ ハッシュタグだ ハッシュタグ
Okay then... Oh right, the hashtag! The hashtag.
ハッシュタグは え こちら
The hashtag is, uh, this one here.
あの さくらみこ新衣装クリスマスライブでね 応援してください
Please cheer for us with #SakuraMikoNewOutfitXmasLIVE.
スクショもたくさん撮ってね
Take lots of screenshots too!
ちょっとスクショタイム
A quick screenshot time.
はい きゅるるん
Yes! Kyururun!
あ かわいい
Ah, cute!
あ かわいい あ かわいい
Ah, cute! Ah, cute!
かわいい あ かわいい
Cute! Ah, cute!
はい かわいい
Yes, cute!
ということでね みんなたくさん撮ってね
So, make sure you all take plenty of pictures.
はい お願いします
Yes, please do!
そして なんと最後に重大告知も
Also, at the very end, there's a major announcement...
ありますので 最後までぜひお見逃しなく
...so please make sure to watch until the end!
ありがとう よろしくね
Thank you! I'm counting on you.
それでは次の曲行きますか
Alright, shall we go to the next song?
こちらにね ご移動させていただきまして
Allow me to move over here.
はい
Okay.
それでは 次の曲行くぞー
Alright! Let's go to the next song!
半端ないぱっぱらぱっぱらぱっぱら
Totally insane pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra
限界突破らっぱらっぱらっぱら
Breaking limits pa-ra pa-ra pa-ra
毎日半端ないぱっぱらぱっぱらぱっぱら
Every day is totally insane pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra
限界突破らっぱらっぱらっぱら
Breaking limits pa-ra pa-ra pa-ra
明日の私に幸あれ
May there be happiness for tomorrow's me.
最適温度
Optimal temperature,
uh 過ぎるゴースト
uh, passing ghosts.
八百万の
Eight million...
嫌な外的要素
...unpleasant external factors.
何の気ないと
Unintentionally...
超あっけらかんと
...super casually.
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの誰かさんにバイバイ
Bye-bye to someone out there interfering without malice.
自分時間だらっとタイム確保 5時9時は死守マスト
Securing my lazy time, must defend the 5-to-9.
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに
And don't forget love, romance, and sweets.
とどのつまり
In the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
...I'm warning you that overwork is prohibited.
ねえ 楽して苦なくして生きてくって難しいな
Hey, it's hard to live easily without suffering, huh?
だって安定 裏技イチャンヅケ 甘い蜜には罠がある
Because stability, cheat codes, pickin' fights... sweet nectar has traps.
やっ
Yah!
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up past noon.
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Play because I want to play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when I'm hungry.
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh if I'm happy.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, it's okay to cry, right?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll do my best today somehow.
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll work hard so I don't have to work hard tomorrow.
怠惰じゃないやこれ多分そうだ
This isn't laziness, probably.
なんやでやることはやっています
I'm doing what needs to be done, somehow.
What? & But
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
It doesn't matter if nobody knows.
私には私のマイルール
I have my own rules.
明日堕落するためにはハイチーズ
Say cheese to be corrupt tomorrow.
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある
Surprisingly, a daily life with love and peace like this...
毎日を生きていたいのてす
...is how I want to live.
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy
ドキドキドキドキしたい
I want to be excited.
Let Let Let me shine
明日天気になれ
May the weather be good tomorrow.
To To To be excite
心もっと踊りたい
I want my heart to dance more.
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday
木金土日月
Thu Fri Sat Sun Mon
辛くなったら歌う
Sing if it gets tough.
ムカついたら愚痴る
Complain if I'm annoyed.
やりたいようにやる
Do as I please.
それができたら苦労しないわ
If I could do that, I wouldn't struggle!
常に一喜一憂
Always wavering between joy and sorrow.
適当にセーブ・リスクは回避しつつ
Saving energy appropriately and avoiding risks...
まぁ頑張るのさ
...well, I'll do my best.
適当にとまでは言うまいが
I won't go so far as to say 'whatever'...
まぁ頑張るのさ
...but well, I'll do my best.
夢の中では
Inside my dreams...
ずっとぐーたらしてやるんだ
I'm going to be lazy forever.
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく
Not for someone else or anything like that,
明日の私の私のため
but for the me of tomorrow.
楽するために苦しいことも
To take it easy, even painful things...
乗り越えちゃうんだからね
...I'll overcome them, you know!
やりたくないことやらないために
To not do what I don't want to do,
やりたくないことやれ
do what I don't want to do.
あれこれって結局頑張れてる？
Wait, does this mean I'm actually doing my best?
私とっても偉いじゃないか！
Aren't I super amazing?!
自分時間堕落タイム確保
Securing my own time, my depravity time.
17時~9時は死守します
I will defend 5 to 9 with my life.
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに
Furthermore, not forgetting love, romance, and sweetness,
とどのつまり
in the end,
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって
saying 'Overwork is trespassing',
注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm issuing a warning too.
ねぇ楽して苦なくして生きてくって
Hey, living comfortably without suffering...
難しいな
...is difficult, isn't it?
だって「安定」「裏技」「一発逆転」
Because 'stability', 'exploits', 'turnarounds'...
甘い蜜には罠がある
...sweet nectar has its traps.
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I want to play, so I play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I get hungry, I eat.
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, it's okay to cry, isn't it?
明日の私のために
For the sake of tomorrow's me,
今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
I'll manage to do my best today too.
明日もう頑張らなくていいように
So that I don't have to try hard tomorrow,
頑張るのさ
I'll do my best.
半端ないぱっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Incredible pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
限界突破っぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits pa-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
毎日半端ないぱっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Every day is incredible pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
限界突破っぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits pa-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
きみがひとりで「XX」してるの知ってるよ
I know you're doing 'XX' all alone.
ビクンビクン震えてさ
Twitching and trembling,
声もダダ漏れなんだわ
your voice is leaking out everywhere.
正直に言っちゃえよ
Just say it honestly.
バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ
It's obvious anyway, so just say it.
効いてんの？
Is it working?
普通普通恥ずかしい？
Normally, normally, is it embarrassing?
みんな隠しているだけ
Everyone's just hiding it.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
きみがひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
I know you're crying all alone.
グスングスン凹んでさ
Sniffling and feeling down,
弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Singing complaints alone in the night.
朝が来るまで一筆コース
A nonstop course until morning comes.
もっと泣いたって
Even if you cry more,
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you as many times as it takes.
もう我慢しないで
Don't hold back anymore,
いっぱい出してね
let it all out.
お願いきみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
慰めさせて
Let me comfort you.
シェイクシェイク
Shake, shake,
愛の才能で
with my talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me,
枯れてしまう
I'll wither away.
濡れていたい
I want to stay wet.
ねぇいいでしょう？
Hey, it's okay, right?
舐め取って
Lick it up,
飲み干したいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to drink it all up.
お願いきみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
頼り散らして
Rely on me completely,
シックラブ
Sick Love,
なんて最高ね
isn't it the best?
分けてくれなきゃ
If you don't share with me,
きみの痛い
your pain,
感じていたい
I want to feel it.
塞いでいたい
I want to block it up.
ねぇいいでしょう？
Hey, it's okay, right?
吸い取って
Suck it out,
救いたいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to save you.
見たい...
I want to see...
きみの中
Inside you.
見たい...
I want to see...
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
きみがひとり悔しがってんの知ってるよ
I know you're feeling frustrated all alone.
ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん
My heart's pounding and soaring,
きみを推すことやめない
I won't stop supporting you.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
きみはできる子知ってるよ
I know you're a capable kid.
つらい時は
When it's tough,
重いくらいで丁度いい
being a bit heavy is just right.
あたしそれでも好きだよ
I still love you regardless.
お願いきみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
名前を呼んでよ
Call my name,
いつだって
anytime,
会いに参上
I'll arrive to see you.
きみはひとりだ
You are alone.
だから歌う
That's why I sing,
ひとりじゃない
you're not alone.
もういいでしょう
It's enough, right?
ソロプレイは
Solo play is
お仕舞いなんだってば
over, I'm telling you.
きみが病める時は
When you are sick,
あたし側にいるわ
I'll be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I'll always be watching over you.
そうよ怖くないのよ
That's right, it's not scary.
お願いきみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
慰めさせて
Let me comfort you.
シェイクシェイク
Shake, shake,
愛の才能で
with my talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me,
枯れてしまう
I'll wither away.
濡れていたい
I want to stay wet.
ねぇいいでしょう？
Hey, it's okay, right?
舐め取って
Lick it up,
飲み干したいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to drink it all up.
お願いきみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
頼り散らして
Rely on me completely,
シックラブ
Sick Love,
なんて最高ね
isn't it the best?
分けてくれなきゃ
If you don't share with me,
きみの痛い
your pain,
感じていたい
I want to feel it.
塞いでいたい
I want to block it up.
ねぇいいでしょう？
Hey, it's okay, right?
吸い取って
Suck it out,
救いたいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to save you.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
きみがひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
I know you're crying all alone.
グスングスン凹んでさ
Sniffling and feeling down,
弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Singing complaints alone in the night.
朝が来るまで一筆コース
A nonstop course until morning comes.
もっと泣いたって
Even if you cry more,
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you as many times as it takes.
もう我慢しないで
Don't hold back anymore,
出してってってってば
I'm telling you to let it all out.
ずうっといっしょ！
Forever Together!
充電器を貸して！
Lend me your charger!
またあなたのせいであたしすり減った
Because of you, I'm worn out again.
終電見逃して
I missed the last train,
またあたしのせいで帰れなくなった
and couldn't go home because of me again.
繋がっていようね
Let's stay connected,
消耗戦に持ち込んで
dragging this into a war of attrition.
お互いに足を引っ張ったアオハル沈殿した思い出で
In the precipitated memories of our youth where we held each other back,
ずっといっしょ！
we'll be together forever!
参観日にだって
Even on observation day,
誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
I felt like no one was watching me.
散々シニカって
Being terribly cynical,
昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
I tried not to expect anything from the city in daylight.
そうやって守った
The solitude I protected like that,
孤独さえめちゃくちゃになった
even that became a mess.
あたい いつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die, I can't help it.
こんな顔だいじにしたいと思えないもん
I just can't bring myself to cherish this face.
共に過ごした日々が
The days we spent together,
ささやかな幸せが
the modest happiness,
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
I hope it becomes an irreplaceable trauma for you.
はなればなれなんて誰が仕掛けたバグだよね？
Being separated is just a bug someone set up, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なぁに？
Q. What is precious to you?
A. 今失くしたそれ
A. That thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now.
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
グロい履歴の中で ずっといっしょ！
together forever in this grotesque history!
もうちょっと普通に
I wanted to think of sad things,
悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
as just sad, a bit more normally.
長調のチューンに
Entrusting my emotions to a major key tune,
感情委託して楽になりたかった
I just wanted to feel at ease.
「せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね」
"Please live your life as hard as you can, at best."
あたい いつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die, I can't help it.
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the mercy of a song like that.
あなただけひとりで
Don't be the only one,
あたしの目を盗んで
to steal my eyes and go off,
幸せになろうなんて思わないで
thinking you can become happy on your own.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から
From the night you dried my hair,
あたしは壊されていたんだよ
I was being broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you as your lifelong regret.
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that won't come off,
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている
it keeps flashing back over and over.
最低だよ
It's the worst.
一緒に居た時の方が あたし可愛かったなぁ
I was cuter when we were together.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なぁに？
Q. What is precious to you?
A. 今失くしたそれ
A. That thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now.
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
他の誰かと眠っていても
even if you are sleeping with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢でずっといっしょ！
we'll be together forever in a matching nightmare!
天天天天天天天天 天天天国地獄国！
Ten Ten Ten Ten... Heaven Hell Country!
Open Sesame
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic where darkness and light intersect.
今宵味わう psychedelic
Taste the psychedelic tonight.
踊り絡まり合う zodiac
A zodiac dancing and intertwining.
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
A tie-break in the game of love.
飾らない存在
An unadorned existence,
ただ気を惹きたい
just wanting to attract attention.
夢見心地 馴れ合い 惑わせたい
Dreamlike, colluding, I want to bewilder.
曖昧 溶けない cocktailは甘い
The ambiguous, undissolving cocktail is sweet.
鮮やかな赤いeye 見つめて限界
Staring at the vivid red eye, to the limit.
月夜に誘われ
Invited by the moonlit night,
天使と悪魔と
angel and devil and...
天使と悪魔が
angels and devils.
偶さか接した
Coincidentally met,
天国地獄の
of heaven and hell,
of heaven and hell.
狭間で出会った
Met in the rift,
天使と悪魔と
angel and devil and...
天使と悪魔が
angels and devils.
集って踊れば
If we gather and dance,
天国地獄の
the gates of heaven and hell,
門が開く
the gates will open.
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic where darkness and light intersect.
今宵味わう psychedelic
Taste the psychedelic tonight.
踊り絡まり合う zodiac
A zodiac dancing and intertwining.
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
A tie-break in the game of love.
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Birth Birth
Death Birth Death
生きた魂を trayに置いて
Place a living soul on the tray.
めくる5枚のcard 揺れるほど
Turn over five cards, enough to shake you.
先にあなたが raiseしたなら
If you raise first,
もう迷わない glass飲み干して
I won't hesitate anymore, drink up the glass.
今夜 All-in 降りない この勝負
Tonight, All-in. I won't fold this game.
いま、天国と地獄をつなぐ門が開いていく。
Now, the gate connecting heaven and hell is opening.
天使と悪魔、死者と生者が入り乱れ、踊り、笑い
Angels and devils, the dead and the living jumbled together, dancing, laughing...
それは世界の終焉であり、
It was the end of the world,
新たなる始まりでもあるのだった。
and also a new beginning.
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death Birth Birth Birth
天天天天天国天
Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Hell
天天天天天国天
Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Hell
月夜に誘われ 天使と悪魔と
Invited by the moonlit night, with an Angel and a Devil.
天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔と
With an Angel and a Devil, with an Angel and a Devil.
偶さか接した天国地獄の
An unexpected encounter of Heaven and Hell,
恍惚消えない果てない moon-night
Ecstasy won't fade, endless moon-night.
天国地獄の 天国地獄の
Of Heaven and Hell, of Heaven and Hell.
狭間で出会った 天使と悪魔と
Met in the rift, an Angel and a Devil.
集って踊れば dance dance dance
If we gather and dance, dance dance dance.
天天天天天国天
Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Heaven Hell
回想中熱くなりお茶いかが? 冷静に大人で
Mid-flashback, getting heated, how about some tea? Calmly acting mature.
ハートは君にまだ教えずにご相談チラチラと
My heart hasn't told you yet, seeking advice with flickering glances.
余裕 身に着けて言う「お相手は You?」
Wearing my composure, I ask, 'Is my partner You?'
ドラマのようなことしない女優
An actress who doesn't do dramatic things.
噛めば噛むほど美味しい lady 例に甘え方を見せてほしい
The more you chew, the tastier it gets. Lady, show me how to be spoiled.
はみ出したい ん～変われないの
I want to break free, hmm, I can't change.
自由型のいい子は好き放題
The free-spirited good girl does whatever she wants.
その塩梅 も～わからないの
I don't even know the balance anymore.
優しいふりしてただ焦ってる
Pretending to be kind, but just impatient.
要求はさりげなくお茶濁し嬉しさをごまかし
My demands are subtle, glossing over them, hiding my joy.
反省会駆け引きを学びたい 裏技をつらつらと
I want to learn tactics at the reflection meeting, listing out cheat codes.
至急きっかけのキュー! 慌てても cute
An urgent cue to start! Even if I panic, I'm cute.
そんな事なんて仕立てないIQ
My IQ isn't built for things like that.
あの手この手も出来ない lady 例におとし方まとめてほしい
I can't use this trick or that. Lady, I want you to summarize how to win you over.
遠慮して ん～はしゃげないの
Holding back, hmm, I can't let loose.
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead everything perfectly, but...
そのボーダー も～超えらんないの
I can't cross that border anymore.
そもそもの話まだ隠してる
To begin with, I'm still hiding the truth.
(読めない読めない) 恋は
(Unreadable, unreadable) Love is...
そっと口角上げ君を魅せ 君を
Softly raising the corners of my mouth, charming you, you...
(包み包み)
(Wrapping up, wrapping up)
そっと心タップ 君を あぁ君を
Softly tapping your heart, you, ah, you...
知りたい
I want to know.
はみ出したい ん～変われないの
I want to break free, hmm, I can't change.
自由型のいい子は好き放題
The free-spirited good girl does whatever she wants.
その塩梅 も～わからないの
I don't even know the balance anymore.
優しいふりしてただ焦って
Pretending to be kind, but just impatient...
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead everything smoothly, but...
そのボーダー も～超えらんないの
I just can't cross that border anymore.
そもそもの話 まだ隠して
I'm still hiding the real story,
見つめてる
and gazing at you.
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, this feeling right now.
空から降ってきたみたい
It feels like it fell from the sky.
特別な季節の色が
The colors of this special season
ときめきを見せるよ
are showing me excitement.
初めて出会った時から
From the moment we first met,
予感に騒ぐ心のMelody
my heart's melody has been stirring with anticipation.
とめられない とまらない なぜ
I can't stop it, it won't stop, why?
届けて 切なさには
Let it reach you... for this heartache,
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
shall we give it a name? "Snow halation".
想いが重なるまで
Until our feelings overlap,
待てずに 悔しいけど好きって純情
I can't wait... it's frustrating, but this love is pure.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
In this slight fever, hesitating is no good.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I accept the courage to dive in! Starting soon!!
音もなく 気配もなく
Without a sound, without a sign,
静かに運命は変わる
fate quietly changes.
これからの未来に胸の
Thinking of the future ahead,
鼓動が早くなる
my heartbeat speeds up.
例えば困った時には
For instance, if you're ever in trouble,
すぐ駆けつけて抱きしめたくて
I want to rush over and hug you immediately.
どこにいても どこでも Fly high
Wherever you are, anywhere, I'll fly high.
急いで いつの間にか
Hurrying, before I knew it,
大きくなりすぎた “True emotion”
this "True emotion" grew too big.
夢だけみてるようじゃ
If I'm only looking at dreams,
つらいよ 恋人は君って言いたい
it hurts. I want to say you're my lover.
優しい目が とまどってるイヤだよ
Your gentle eyes are bewildered... I don't like that.
このまま一気に愛情 あずけて Please!!
Just let me give you all this love at once, Please!!
届けて 切なさには
Let it reach you... for this heartache,
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
shall we give it a name? "Snow halation".
想いが重なるまで
Until our feelings overlap,
待てずに 悔しいけど好きって純情
I can't wait... it's frustrating, but this love is pure.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
In this slight fever, hesitating is no good.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I accept the courage to dive in! Starting soon!!
はーい！みんな楽しんでくれてますかー？
Haaai! Is everyone having fun?
ゲストもね、たくさん来てくださいました！
Lots of guests came too!
みんなありがとうー！
Thank you everyone!
そして、見てくださーい！
And, please look!
ステージもちょっとね、ぐるっと回転して
The stage spun around a bit,
外にやってきました！すごくないですか？
and we came outside! Isn't it amazing?
ちょっとイルミネーションもね、きれいでね
The illuminations are beautiful too, right?
もうクリスマスって感じで…ちょっと
It really feels like Christmas... a little
ま、ちょっと若干肌寒いですけどね！
Well, it is slightly chilly though!
もうすんごいきれいだよね、見て！すごい！
It's super beautiful, look! Wow!
すごーい！うわー
Amazing! Wow!
はい。どうもありがとうございます。
Yes. Thank you very much.
そして…なんと次で最後の曲になるんですが
And... actually, the next song will be the last one,
なんと！次の曲は…新曲です！わー！
but believe it or not! The next song is... a new song! Waa!
みこちゃん、ファーストアルバム以来のね、
This is Miko-chan's first,
ソロの新曲となります。
new solo song since the first album.
えー、ソロライブを経て、
After the solo live,
みこがまた新たな一歩を踏み出す曲となっております。
this song marks a new step forward for Miko.
それでは、聴いてください。
So then, please listen.
『咲き誇れアイドル』
'Sakihokore Idol'
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging
君と夢見るんだ
I'll dream with you
不器用で悪いか
So what if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I will bloom proudly
初のイベント
First event
余裕なしで
with no composure
そんな私が夢を見ました
Someone like me had a dream
アイドルという生き方
The way of life called 'Idol'
憧れて
Yearning for it
「無敵エリート」
'Invincible Elite'
笑顔はチート
Smiles are a cheat
こんな私を見てくれる君
You, who watches someone like me
好きなとこはどこですか？
What parts do you like?
わがままを許して
Forgive my selfishness
ステージ経験
Stage experience
涙滲んで
tears welling up
それでも絶対負けたくない
Even so, I absolutely don't want to lose
サクラにメッセージ乗せて届け
Carry this message on the cherry blossoms
愛で溢れますように
May it overflow with love
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging
君と夢見るんだ
I'll dream with you
不器用で悪いか
So what if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a delusion
私らしく桜色
Cherry blossom colored, just like me
ね？
Right?
磨いたスキル 実力発揮
Polished skills, demonstrating ability
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
The days I can enjoy it have increased
アイドルとして生きてる
Living as an idol
君のおかげ
Thanks to you
アホ毛はキュート！
Ahoge is cute!
落ち込むルート
Route to feeling down
そんな私についてきてよね
Follow someone like me, okay?
ドジなとこも許されて
Forgiven for my clumsiness too
最強じゃん！
Isn't that the strongest!
痛いの痛いの
Pain, pain
グッと飲み込んで
swallow it down tight
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to increase smiles with a smile
桜前線が君の街に
The cherry blossom front to your town
春を届けるように
To deliver spring
アイドルだけは
Being an idol is the one thing
譲りたくないんだ
I don't want to give up
君に魅せたいんだ
I want to show you
理想へ挑むよ
I'll challenge my ideals
駆け抜ける
Running through
最高景色見せたげる
I'll show you the best scenery
信じていいよ
You can believe in me
桜を
The cherry blossoms
さぁ皆で咲かそう
Come on, let's bloom together
みんなで咲かそう
Let's bloom together
満開のピンクで
With pink in full bloom
世界染めて
dyeing the world
あぁ この涙はね
Ah, these tears, you see
悲しい方じゃないから
aren't the sad kind
安心して
so don't worry
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging
君と夢見るんだ
I'll dream with you
不器用で悪いか
So what if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a delusion
私らしく桜色
Cherry blossom colored, just like me
桜色
Cherry blossom colored
ね？
Right?
みんなー Twinkle Idol Christmas 新衣装お披露目ライブを見てくれて
Everyone! Thanks for watching the Twinkle Idol Christmas New Outfit Reveal Live!
どうもありがとー！
Thank you so much!
ここで、告知が３つあります！
I have three announcements here!
まずは、こちら！
First is this!
200万人記念 ルームウェア衣装お披露目記念グッズが発売されます！
The 2 Million Subscribers Room Wear Outfit Reveal Commemorative Goods are on sale!
キービジュアルは おるだん先生に描いてもらいました！
The key visual was drawn by Ordan-sensei!
いつもありがとうございます！
Thank you always!
イラストのテーマは お部屋でのんびりしているみこです
The theme of the illustration is Miko relaxing in her room.
それでは、ひとつずつ見ていきましょう！
Let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら リバーシブルブランケット
First is this, the Reversible Blanket.
表には35P、裏にはみこの大きなイラストが描いてあります
It has 35P on the front, and a large illustration of Miko on the back.
丸く包まれると みんなも35Pぬいぐるみになっちゃうよー
If you wrap yourself up in it, you'll become a 35P plushie too!
続いて みこちとおそろい35Pヘアバンド
Next is the Matching with Mikochi 35P Hair Band.
みこの新衣装とおそろいのヘアバンドです
It's a hair band that matches Miko's new outfit.
毎日使いができるアイテムでーす
It's an item you can use every day.
使ってね
Please use it!
次は みこちの愛用35Pマグカップです
Next is Mikochi's Favorite 35P Mug Cup.
お耳もついてるマグカップなんだよー
It's a mug cup that even has ears!
ついに再現できました！
We finally reproduced it!
飲み物を入れてもよし 小物入れにするもよし
You can put drinks in it, or use it to hold small items.
素敵なおうち時間のお供に使ってね
Please use it to accompany your wonderful time at home.
最後は ルームウェアみこちの35Pぎゅっ♡おねんねぬいぐるみです
Lastly, the Room Wear Mikochi's 35P Hug♡Sleepy Plushie.
ルームウェア衣装のみこが ぬいぐるみになりましたー
Miko in her room wear outfit has become a plushie!
みんなも一緒におやすみしようねー
Let's all say goodnight together, okay?
フルセットはこんな感じです
The full set looks like this.
そしてそして
And, and!
フルセット特典はポストカードです！
The full set bonus is a postcard!
今回は箔押しの複製サインとメッセージ付きになっております
This time it comes with a foil-stamped reproduction signature and message.
みんなー
Everyone,
ぜひぜひ購入してくださいねー！
please definitely buy it!
告知２つ目はこちら！
Here is the second announcement!
本日初披露した新曲『咲き誇れアイドル』が
The new song revealed today, 'Sakihokore Idol',
本日0時から配信開始！
starts streaming from 12:00 AM today!
ファーストソロライブを終えて 次のステージに向かっていく気持ちを
The feelings of heading towards the next stage after finishing the first solo live
HoneyWorksさんに書き下ろしていただきました！
were written into a song by HoneyWorks!
そしてそしてこのあと
And, and after this,
『咲き誇れアイドル』のMVがプレミア公開となります！
the MV for 'Sakihokore Idol' will have its premiere!
とってもかわいいので
It's super cute,
みんなたくさん聴いて見てくださいねー
so everyone please listen and watch it a lot!
告知３つ目はこちら！
Here is the third announcement!
なーんと！
Surprisingly!
さくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗のコラボが 2026年も決定しましたー！
The Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collaboration has been confirmed for 2026!
2026年も決定しましたー！
Confirmed for 2026 too!
なんと４回目ですよー
It's actually the 4th time!
えー、今回の開催期間は
Um, the period this time is
2026年2月20日から 3月31日までです！
from February 20, 2026 to March 31st!
やったー！
Yay!
本当にね、こんなに長く続いているのは みんなのおかげでもありますし
Really, the fact that it's continued this long is thanks to everyone,
鳴門鯛焼本舗さん、本当にありがとうございます！
and Naruto Taiyaki Honpo, thank you so much!
詳細は、後日
Details will be
またXなどで告知するので 楽しみにしててくださいねー
announced later on X etc., so please look forward to it!
今日は本当にありがとう、みんなー！
Thank you so much for today, everyone!
メリークリスマース！
Merry Christmas!
おつみこでしたー！
Otsumiko!
バイバーイ！
Bye bye!